emedicinehealth.com 2006-12-18

# eMedicine Health - Consumer First Aid and Health Information

eMedicine recognizes that privacy is a personal right and a critical concern of individuals. This concern is heightened when using the World Wide Web and particularly when using a healthcare-related site. We invite users of the eMedicine medical reference and our other services to familiarize themselves with our privacy policy, which delineates how eMedicine obtains and uses personal information. The policy is divided into the following sections:

  * Why we obtain information about use of our site
  * What information is obtained and how it is used
  * What information is gathered for continuing medical education (CME) and continuing education (CE)
  * What information is gathered by other corporate entities involved with our site
  * What information is shared and with whom it is shared
  * Summary statement

### Why we obtain information about use of our site

eMedicine gathers 3 basic types of information from our users. First, our contributing physicians, authors, and editors create and maintain the content of the site using the patented Group Publishing System™. This system requires appropriate identification and password-secured authorization of contributors to the site.

Second, users who choose to register provide information. This helps us to understand who our users are and to shape our content accordingly.

Third, we collect information about site use. This helps us to identify needs, such as the amount of serving power required, and to communicate generalized statistics about usage numbers, page views, and visit durations to investors, sponsors, and advertisers.

### What information is obtained and how it is used

Contributing physician authors and editors submit contact and credential information. We use contact information to help manage the site and to facilitate communication between authors and editors. Each article displays contributors’ basic credential information and affiliations. eMedicine stores other information about contributors’ education, training, and accomplishments in a secure manner and provides this data only to CME and CE certifying bodies when requested.

Visitors may access some eMedicine content without registering and providing personally identifiable information. We track information provided to us by individuals’ browsers, including originating Web sites (known as "referring URLs"), types of browsers used, times and dates of site visits, and other information that does not personally identify users.

We only require registration to access certain parts of the eMedicine site. Users who choose to provide information about themselves help us to assess the interests of our audience. Within the registration process, we clearly mark which information fields are required and which fields are optional. "Opt-in" and "opt-out" features allow our registered users to receive eMedicine newsletters and information from eMedicine sponsors and partners.

Registered users may be contacted by eMedicine in order for us to provide updates about the site. eMedicine makes use of aggregate information (such as the percentage of users who are MDs) to inform sponsors, advertisers, and other corporate partners about our users in general. No identifying or individual registration information is shared with sponsors or any other corporation. In the future, we may allow an outside agency, such as an accounting firm, access to individual information solely for verification and counting purposes. 

_Use of Cookies_

eMedicine obtains information about visitors' site use and offers features such as personalized start pages. Some of this information is gathered through exchange of cookies, which are small packets of information that flow from the site to the users' computers and back. Browsers can be set to accept or reject cookies or to notify users each time a cookie is sent. If a browser is set to reject cookies, Web sites that are cookie enabled will not recognize visitors when they return to the Web site, and some Web site functionality may be lost. Browser Help sections contain instructions regarding cookie acceptance/rejection settings.

Cookies do not normally contain personally identifiable information; however, we may associate users’ registration information with cookies our Web site places on the users’ computer hard drives. Associating a cookie with registration data allows us to deliver personalized start pages and enables our Web site to recognize user names and passwords, thus permitting regular visitors to bypass the sign-in process. Without cookies, this function is not possible.

A user’s personal information may be used to help us target our advertising or marketing efforts. For example, a user registering as an ophthalmologist may receive advertising for new vision products (although the advertiser will not have access to any individually identifiable information).

### What information is gathered for CME and CE

When registering for a CME or CE activity through our Web site, we collect certain personally identifiable information, such as names, email addresses, mailing addresses, and credit card numbers. In addition to personally identifiable information, we collect aggregated personally unidentifiable information about activities undertaken by our users. We use information collected through CME and CE activities in the following ways: 

i. eMedicine is accredited by the Accreditation Council for Continuing Medical Education (ACCME) to provide CME for physicians. As an ACCME-accredited entity, we are required to periodically submit aggregated data about CME participants and the CME activities we certify. 

ii. Commercial supporters of CME and CE activities on our Web site receive only aggregated data that are relevant to their interests and/or the courses they support.

iii. eMedicine editorial and customer support staff have internal access to files containing personally identifiable information, including evaluation forms and aggregated CME and CE participant information. These files can be accessed in order to respond to questions or comments. Our staff may also use personally identifiable information, including registration information and evaluation data, when assessing educational needs and planning marketing activities. 

### What information is gathered by other corporate entities involved with our site

We use Webtrends™ software to track how many page views and hits we deliver, length of stay on the site, and frequency with which each article is visited. We use this information only in aggregate form and do not share or store individual or identifying information. We share some of this aggregate information with other corporations or sponsors. For example, we might share that eMedicine has experienced growth in traffic over a period of time, averaging an increase of 20-25%.

eMedicine also has relationships with companies that supply advertisements to the site. eMedicine uses the services of 24/7 Real Media for the serving and/or targeting of ads, promotions, and other marketing messages. Clicking on a link or banner at the eMedicine site may send users to another site that may gather information about its users. eMedicine has no control over the privacy policies of other organizations or sites. Some of our advertising partners may use cookies on our site despite our stated preference that they not use cookie information to track our customers’ activities once they leave our sites. However, because of the way advertisements are served on our Web sites, we do not have total 

### What information is shared and with whom it is shared

As discussed above, we display contributor credentials on the site. eMedicine shares only aggregate information about site use and user demographics. eMedicine uses this aggregate information internally to help us determine resource needs and develop content. This information has been presented at academic meetings, including the Scientific Assembly of the Society for Academic Emergency Medicine in the Education Innovations section. We share some of this aggregate information, such as overall demographics, number of visits from different countries, and user traffic information, with corporations.

### Summary statement

eMedicine gathers information needed to operate the site and to understand the demographics of our users via direct registration. We obtain additional information about site traffic and use via cookies and Webtrends™. With the exception of author and editor credentials, which are publicly displayed on the site, we do not share, exchange, or sell personal information to any corporate entity. We share some demographic and use information in aggregate form only. Occasionally, information from required "opt-in" and "opt-out" choices may be used to directly communicate with contributors and registered users in order to manage the site and update users. Companies that supply us with ads may also obtain information via cookies or when users click on a link that sends them from our sites.
